本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：Ｊ小糯    Soomii    红豆包    Iz
校对：Ｊ小糯      时间轴：grace
■
后期：鱼骨头      总监：stephanie
《开心汉堡店》
第一季第十二集
■
海洋大道正在准备迎接今年的龙虾节
Ocean Avenue is gearing up for this year's Lobsterfest,
这就意味着
and that mean
我们一直关注的热带风暴正移向海洋
old tropical storm we've been watching is moving out to sea,
这个周末可以快活快活了
which means perfect weekend weather!
我擦
Ugh! Damn it!
如果你听到隆隆雷声
So if you think you hear thunder,
那只是我的胃在捣乱
it's just my stomach growling.
我超爱龙虾
I love lobster.
这货真是朵奇葩
This guy is unbelievable.
别再叨叨龙虾节了
Stop pimping for Lobsterfest!
那我来扮扮龙虾吧
And start primping for Lobsterfest.
扮相真不错
Looking primpy.
啥都不许扮
No, no primping for anything!
干嘛发这么大火啊  消消气
Why are you so grumpy? Come on.
你知道的啊
You know why.
做汉堡的在海鲜城里混  能高兴得起来么
It's no fun being a burger man in a seafood town.
我讨厌龙虾和傻逼龙虾节
I hate lobsters and their stupid fest.
再说  我对龙虾过敏
Plus, I'm allergic.
才没有呢
No, you're not.
我会过敏  记得咱俩第一次约会么
Yeah, I'm allergic. Remember our first date?
我当然记得啊
Yeah, I remember our first date.
你当时紧张兮兮的
You were a nervous wreck.
我那是过敏...  算了不提了
I was having an allergic reac... Never mind.
你们几个在那儿瞅啥呢
Hey, what are you guys looking at over there?
没什么啊
Um, nothing.
就是些男男女女  做爱做的事呗
Just pictures of people... doing it.
是么  等等  这个不是色情图片
Oh. Hey, wait a minute. That's not porn.
你居然把龙虾节传单带了回来
You brought a Lobsterfest brochure into this house?
-我们今年可以参加吗  -想都别想
- Can we please go this year? - Absolutely not.
可是龙虾节超好玩的
Ugh! But there's so much fun stuff happening.
比如  展示世界上最大的黄油桶
Unveiling of the world's largest butter vat, for instance.
为龙虾皇后
The coronation of
和可爱的龙虾女仆们举行加冕仪式
the Lobster Queen and her court of lovely Lobster Maidens.
"锦绣三重唱"担任现场伴奏乐队
Entertainment by John Van Horton and the music extrusion.
我还蛮喜欢那个乐队的
I do love those guys.
跟你说吧  吉恩
As a matter of fact, Gene,
你就是在那个乐队演出时怀上的
you were conceived to a JVH song.
我打算报答他们一下
And I plan to return the favor.
见鬼  你来啦  雨果
Oh, great. I mean, hi, Hugo.
鲍勃  我无意中注意到
You know, I couldn't help but notice, Bob,
整条街就你们家窗户上
uh, yours is the only window on the street
没贴龙虾节海报
without a Lobsterfest poster in it.
-是的  -能解释一下么
- Yeah. - Why might that be?
因为龙虾节就是个傻逼节
Well, because Lobsterfest is stupid!
-你说什么  -我来搞定  罗恩
- What? - I'll handle this, Ron.
把这张海报贴上去  这是规矩
Put the sign up. It's the law.
-谁家的规矩  -我家的规矩
- It's the law? - Martial law.
我是今年的龙虾节大元帅
I'm grand marshal of the fest this year!
雨果  肩带很炫嘛
Hugo, such a fancy sash.
你好像扮演"嘉莉妹妹"的西席・斯贝西克
You look like Sissy Spacek in Carrie. Ha.
谢了
Oh, thank you.
雨果  作为一名卫生检查员
But, Hugo, as a health inspector,
你肯定知道龙虾有多恶心  是吧
you must know how disgusting lobsters are, right?
它们是食底泥动物  整天吃垃圾
They're bottom feeders that eat garbage all day.
主要以水底有机沉积物为食的底栖动物
它们喜欢吃垃圾
Huh, they like garbage?
那它们一定要尝尝这里
Then they must eat here!
啃啃你的脸  鲍勃
In your face, Bob.
再啃啃你的窗户
And now in your window!
来  罗恩  我俩扮成龙虾
Come on, Ron, let's make like a lobster
然后把虾皮带出去
and get the shell out of here.
好
All right.
系上你的围嘴
龙虾节
两位里面请
Hey, my two best customers!
两个汉堡  马上就来
Two burgers coming up.
先不来汉堡了  鲍勃
No burgers for me, Bob.
我的胃得给龙虾留些地方
I'm saving my appetite for Lobsterfest.
我也不要了  老鲍
None for me either, Bobby.
我过来就是想显摆显摆新买的龙虾钳
I just come by to show you my new lobster cracker.
看
Check it out.
钛金钳身  防油握柄
Titanium with butter-resistant grips.
宇航员专用款
It's the one the astronauts used.
泰迪  你觉得宇航员会带这玩意上天么
Teddy, you think the astronauts brought a lobster cracker to space?
会啊  盒子上就这么写的  你瞧
Yeah. That's what it says on the box. Look.
"宇航员升天专用"
"The one the astronauts used in space!"
这玩意花了我49块钱呢
I spent $49 on this.
你们几个小屁孩长大了呢
Hey, I bet you kids are old enough
可以自己去参加龙虾节了吧
to crack your own claws this year, right?
我们不过龙虾节
We don't celebrate Lobsterfest.
-什么  -就像犹太人不过圣诞节
- What?! - We're like Jews on Christmas.
或是在光明节上说服犹太人信奉基督教
Or Jews for Jesus on Hanukkah.
光明节是犹太人的节日
相当于基督教的圣诞节
这就好比我独自坐在蕾丝酒吧
Or me at a lesbian bar.
昨夜
Last night.
我在一家蕾丝酒吧看了场冰球赛  鲍勃
Watched a hockey game at a lesbian bar, Bob.
我好像变成了一个透明人
It was like I was invisible. Uh...
瓦格斯塔夫小学
谁知道在胰腺部位聚集的这种美味浆糊
And who knows the name of the delicious paste that collects here
叫什么啊
in the pancreas?
-龙虾肝  -回答正确
- Tomalley! - Correct.
打扰一下  勒邦姿老师
Excuse me, Miss Labonz?
请说  露易丝
Yes, Louise.
我们家不过龙虾节
My family doesn't observe Lobsterfest.
所以应该准我免上此课
I should be excused from class,
反正上不上你都得给我A
and/or given an A.
谢谢  晚安
Thank you. Good night.
露易丝  一般情况下我不会搬出这句话
Louise, I don't normally use this argument,
大家都要做的事  你也得做
but if everyone else is doing it, you should, too.
听我说  同学们
Attention, students.
热带风暴转向了
The tropical storm has changed course
并升级为飓风
and has been upgraded to a hurricane.
它随时都会袭击这里
It could hit town at any moment.
别担心  我们备有紧急方案
Don't worry. We have an emergency plan.
名叫"据理分析"
It's called "Talking It Through".
同学们  有谁认为  飓风的形成
Now, who here thinks the hurricane was caused
是因为有人做了坏事而引起的
by something bad they did?
你来说说  尼古拉斯
What about you, Nicholas?
你和我说过的那件事  自信点说出来
That thing you told me? In confidence?
说出来
Say it.
我在沙发上打飞机
I rub my genitals on the couch.
我们都会因你而亡
We're all gonna die because of you!
这种鬼天气只有龙虾会喜欢
It's weather only a lobster could love,
但非常遗憾  今年不会举行龙虾节了
but sadly, there will be no Lobsterfest.
本台记者也要撤下他的围嘴了
This reporter is getting his bib off.
你个二货  败家的预报员
Ha, ha! Stupid, failure weatherman,
还有你们那个败家的龙虾节
and your failed Lobsterfest.
你们那个龇牙咧嘴的红海臭虫神哪儿去了呀
Where's your ugly red sea bug God now?!
好了  手拉手
All right, hold hands.
快进来  去地下室
Come on, down to the basement.
鲍勃  我们必须得关门
Bob, we have to close.
飓风要来了
A hurricane is coming!
我知道  这样不是很棒吗
I know. Isn't it great?
龙虾节被取消了哦
Lobsterfest is cancelled!
然后全市所有人都饿着肚子爬过来
So this town is gonna be crawling with empty bellies
吃鲍家的汉堡  宝贝
ready to eat Bob's burgers, baby!
鲍勃  你疯了
Bob, you're crazy.
你才疯了呢
I think you're crazy!
飓风天气不卖汉堡才是疯子呢
'Cause it's crazy not to sell burgers during a hurricane!
开心汉堡店正常营业
Bob's burgers is open for business!
你就这点本事吗  飓风
Is that all you got, storm?
风铃
Wind chimes! Aah!
鲍勃  我觉得现在营业很不安全
Bob, I'm not sure staying open is safe.
我想  飓风会把这里撕个稀巴烂
Suppose the hurricane tears right through here.
我要赌一把
I'll chance it!
你看我把谁带来了
Look who I found trying to stay dry in the bounce house.
在充气屋里躲雨的全体龙虾皇家女仆
The entire Royal Court of Lobster Maidens.
可怜的小妞们
Oh, you poor things!
欢迎各位殿下莅临寒舍
Welcome, your highnesseses.
从今往后  你们就是皇家奶牛了
Uh, you are henceforth known as the royal cows.
鲍勃
Bob!
或者  类似的东西吧
Ah, well, something like that.
我去做几个汉堡
I'll go throw on some burgers.
热咖啡马上来
Hot coffee coming up!
我更想用嘴裹住那个啤酒龙头
I'd really rather get my lips around that beer tap.
-大家好  -你好  格雷琴
- Hi, guys. - Hey, Gretchen!
哎哟  龙虾女仆
Oh, Lobster Maiden!
泰迪  这位是格雷琴
Teddy, this is Gretchen.
-我的头发一直是她剪的  -你好
- She cuts my hair. - How you doing?
你还在警察酒吧上夜班么
Hey, are you still working nights at the cop bar?
不了  都是手不老实惹的祸
Nah, there was a groping incident.
我道歉了  但还是被开除了
I apologized, but they fired me anyway.
-她喝高了  -确实
- Oh, she's too much. - Really is.
-这儿能进吗  -能啊
- Hey, you open? Mm-hmm.
-有吃的吗  -有啊
- You got food? - Yup.
-有啤酒吗  -还用问吗
- Beer? - Absolutely!
-那气氛呢  -这个嘛...
- Atmosphere? - Yeah... Nah...
就这儿了
Ah, good enough.
老鲍  我觉得这样发展下去很有派对氛围
Whoa, Bobby, I think this might develop into a party type situation!
你们几个  老实待在地下室
You kids stay down in the basement.
我已经选了一角作为浴室
I already picked a corner for the bathroom.
就是那个  我去过的
That one, where I went.
那我要那边那个角落
And I picked that corner.
这样就有两个浴室了
Hey, we've got two bathrooms!
老妈  我要上去了
Mom, I'm coming up!
老老实实待在那儿
Just stay down there.
飓风过后
They're gonna need you
留待你们重整家园  延续香火
to help repopulate the earth when this is all over.
好恶心  你想要我们互相交配吗
Ew! You want us to mate with each other?!
不  你们得跟别人家的孩子
No, you'll mate with the other kids
在别人家的地下室交配
in other basements.
你们继续
Keep talking.
好棒  "锦绣三重奏"不插电演奏会
All right! JVH unplugged!
湿嗒嗒的银发羞嗒嗒地甩
Look at all that wet gray hair.
鲍鲍你看  雨果来了
Oh, Bobby, look at Hugo.
还有可怜的落汤鸡罗恩
Oh, and poor wet Ron.
-是不是很滑稽  -鲍鲍
- Yeah. Isn't it hilarious? - Bobby.
好啦  我去开门
All right, I'll let them in.
我只是想让他们欣赏一下我的菊花
I just want to give them a pressed ham first.
快住手
Stop it!
求求你  答应我嘛
Come on, let me.
那好吧
All right.
抱歉把你家的餐巾纸都用光了
Sorry for using all of your napkins.
鲍勃  谢谢你让我们进来
I want to thank you for bringing us in, Bob.
那都是琳达的意思
It was totally Linda's idea.
她可真是善解人意
She is so damn considerate!
你什么都有  而我却一无所有
You have everything, and I have nothing.
苍天  我好孤独
God, so alone!
龙虾节是我的全部
Lobsterfest was all I had.
现在也没了
And now that's gone, too.
我活着就是一个笑柄
Look at me. I'm a joke!
没错  真糟糕
Yeah, that's too bad.
鲍鲍  龙虾女仆们
Hey, Bobby, some of the Lobster Maidens
很想玩湿衣大赛
are open to the idea of a wet gown contest.
提供个奖品怎么样
Want to put up a prize?
毛巾行么
Uh, how about a towel?
我的老天  这句真好笑
Ha! Oh, my God. That's so funny.
格雷琴  来认识下雨果
Gretchen, have you, uh, met Hugo?
他本来是龙虾节的大元帅来着
He was gonna be grand marshal at the Lobsterfest.
肩带很威武嘛
Ooh. Nice sash.
有没有拿下来过
Ever take it off?
老实说  星期一
Well, actually, on Monday,
我得把它拿去干洗  然后还回去
I have to dry-clean it and give it back.
雨果 格雷琴对权威人物很感兴趣
Uh, Hugo, Gretchen is into authority figures.
警察  消防员  甚至邮递员
Cops, firemen, even mailmen,
只要有重大固定路线就行
if they have an important route.
天啊  我也是
Oh, my Gosh. So am I!
什么  你对邮递员感兴趣么
What, you're into mailmen?
如果他们有重大固定路线的话
Well, if they have an important route.
我觉得鲍勃想说的是
I think what Bob's saying is,
她喜欢佩戴勋章的男人
she likes a man with a badge.
你不是有一个么
You have a badge.
格雷琴
Hey, Gretchen!
干嘛
Huh?
雨果还是个卫生检查员
Hey, Hugo's also a health inspector.
就像是食品治安官
That's like being a food sheriff.
这是我的勋章
This is my badge.
有点小啊
Kind of small.
你有枪么
You got a gun?
没有  实际上  我没有佩枪的资格
Uh, no. Actually, I'm not, uh... licensed to carry a firearm.
但我有食品安全检测仪
I do have a food safety thermometer,
它非常的敏锐
and it's very sharp.
雨果  拿出来看看
Pull it out, Hugo.
对啊  雨果  拿出来看看
Yeah, pull it out, Hugo.
小心点
Whoa! Watch out.
就是这个玩意啊
Here it is. Ooh.
不安全范围
"Unsafe Range".
我喜欢鲍鱼的颜色粉嫩一些
I like my pork a little pink.
(ˉˉ" )没错
你们懂的
蒂娜  你在干什么
Tina, what are you doing?
我在列交配清单
I'm working on my mating list
重整家园时会用到的
for when we have to repopulate the world.
我看看
Let me see.
同性恋  同性恋
Gay. Gay.
虚拟人物
Mythical creature.
同性恋虚拟人物
Gay mythical creature.
祝你好运
Good luck.
各位  我们这是在浪费时间
Guys, we're wasting time here.
我们得溜出去
We got to sneak out.
溜出去  可是外面正在刮飓风啊
Sneak out? But there's a hurricane.
这才是重头戏
That's my point.
我们应该出去  在暴风雨中  抢劫
We should be out there, in the wind and rain, looting!
抢劫
Looting?!
具体要怎样抢呢
So how do we do this looting thing exactly?
简单的很
It's easy.
能拿走的  就可以拿着走了
You grab anything that's not nailed down.
能拿走的  这块砖头可以吗
Anything? Like this brick?
-它是你的了  -免费砖头
- It's yours. - Free brick!
免费硬币
Free quarter.
免费号码
Free phone numbers.
免费海藻
Free seaweed.
吉恩  免费木板
Gene, free plywood.
鲍勃  收银机打不开了
Hey, Bob, the cash register won't open,
还有  你上汉堡的速度过快
and you're serving burgers so fast,
我都记不清该收谁的欠条了
I don't even know who to get an IOU from.
放松  琳达  我来处理
Relax, Linda. I'll take care of it.
听我说  听我说
Hey, hey, hey, hey, listen up, listen up.
你们都是我的朋友
You're all my friends.
朋友不收朋友的钱
And friends don't charge friends.
今晚汉堡免费
The burgers are free, people!
所有食物全部免费
Everything is gonna be free!
鲍勃  飓风天气营业的意义
Bob, I thought the point of staying open
是为了多赚点钱
during a hurricane was to make money!
这比赚钱重要多了  琳
This is way more important than money, Lin!
龙虾节死翘翘了
Lobsterfest is dead.
鲍堡节取而代之
Bobsterfest killed it!
鲍堡节万岁
Long live Bobsterfest!
抢劫好艰辛啊
Looting is hard.
我想抢屁股
Ah, I think I'm getting loot glutes.
这些东西可真没档次
This stuff sucks.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
快看
Hello.
爬过来一只什么
What have we here?
也许他迷路了
Maybe he's lost.
看看它的脖子
Check his collar.
抓住它  吉恩
Get him, Gene!
这个小家伙看起来像是掉进了办公用品中
Looks like this little guy got into some office supplies.
没错  那两个皮套碍眼死了
Yeah, those rubber bands don't look comfortable.
你应该把它拿掉
You should take them off.
这是我们唯一的一次机会
This is our one chance to see
体验传说中的传说
what everyone else is talking about.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
今晚有龙虾吃呗
We're gonna eat lobster tonight!
可这背离了我们一直以来的信仰
But that goes against everything we were raised to believe in!
这不是背离我们的信仰
It doesn't go against everything, okay?
不过这是个很好的开始
But it's a start.
偷尝禁果的机会来了
Now's our chance to taste the forbidden fruit
一生一次的机会终于来了
that has been kept from us our whole lives.
你们支持我吗
Are you with me?
-支持  -好啊
- Yeah! - Okay.
一位慷慨人士把龙虾节变成了鲍堡节
And one man's generosity has turned Lobsterfest into Bobsterfest.
我们来采访一下当事人  鲍勃
We're trying to get a word with Bob himself here.
我爱你  斯科特・佰格滋
I love you, Scott Bags!
话筒底下连着线呢
Yeah, there's a cable on that.
你别乱跑啊
You can't go all the way over there.
跟我走
You come with me!
好的  好的
Yeah, okay.
跟我走
You come with me!
可以把麦克风还给我吗
Can I... can I get my mic back, please?
你来拿呀
You come up and get it.
把麦克风还给我
Give me the mic!
鲍勃  鲍勃  鲍勃
Bob! Bob! Bob...!
感觉好怪异
This feels weird!
老兄
Hey, bro.
我是不是挑起了你的欲望  雨果
Did I hook you up or what, Hugo?
我这是要去哪里  这边吗
Hey, where are we going now? Over here?
谁说了算啊
Who decides which way we go?
那位是琳达  我老婆
There's Linda, my wife!
琳达  你看起来很生气
Hey, Linda, you look mad.
咱们走另外一边吧
Let's go the other way.
转回去  拜  琳达
Turn around. Bye, Linda.
感觉如何啊  鲍勃
How you feeling, Bob?
什么
What?
天哪  琳
Oh, my God. Lin!
餐馆全毁了
The restaurant's destroyed.
龙卷风横扫这里  我们被袭了
The hurricane swept right through here, we got hit!
事实上  龙卷风转向了  鲍勃
Actually, the hurricane missed us, Bob.
外面景色动人
It's beautiful out.
你就是龙卷风  傻逼
You were the hurricane, schmuck!
你好  格雷琴
Hey, Gretchen.
你有我能穿的运动裤吗
Do you have some sweat pants I can put on?
琳达
Linda.
琳达  我感觉很不舒服
Linda. I don't feel well.
你瞅瞅你这幅鬼样子
I can't even look at you.
我感觉很不舒服
I don't feel well.
这是我整的吗
I did this?
你和那帮乌合之众
You and the mob you incited
喝着免费啤酒  吃着免费汉堡
with free beer and burgers.
谁把我的票插弄弯了
Oh, who bent my little spindle thing?
你只注意到这个吗
That's what you notice?!
好了  琳  现在看起来是很糟糕
Okay, Lin, it looks bad now,
但是我们昨晚交了很多新朋友啊
but we made a lot of new friends last night.
一旦我鲍勃开口求助
Once word spreads that Bob needs help,
这里就会重新挤满人
this place will be jammed again.
而最大的问题其实是
The biggest problem is gonna be
给需要工作的人找个活干
finding a job for everybody who wants one.
天啊  我很担心这东西
Gee, I'm worried about this,
我真的很喜欢它
I really love it.
好了  昨晚的技术问题已经解决了
Okay, technical problems from last night have been resolved.
吹风机  加上铁板  还有烤箱
Hair dryer plus waffle iron plus toaster
就等于开水
equals boiling water.
在把它煮熟前  要怎么杀死它啊
So how do we kill this guy before we boil him?
我们可以教龙虾开车
We could teach the lobster to drive
然后等着看它被车撞死
and wait until it gets into an accident.
或者雇个刺客
Or we could hire an assassin.
不  傻逼  龙虾要活着煮才对
No, idiots, you boil lobsters alive.
什么  听起来不对劲啊
What?! That doesn't sound right.
没错  把它煮到死
Yep. Until he's dead.
然后再多煮一会
And then we boil him some more.
要开煮了哦
Here we go.
等等  怎么感觉有点不对劲呢
Wait, this does'nt feel right.
在小黑屋里往脖子上掖条手纸就开吃了么
Doing it in a dark room with toilet paper around my neck?
我还以为第一次吃龙虾会特别一点
I thought my first time eating lobster would be special.
现在  请随着小吉米夫妇
And now please join Mr. and Mrs. Jimmy Jr.
吃下他们人生中的第一只龙虾
as they eat their first lobster!
我也以为第一次吃龙虾会与众不同呢
I thought my first time eating lobster would be different, too.
后台
吉恩  吉恩
Gene! Gene!
他们在热水桶里等着你呢  吉恩
They're waiting for you in the hot tub, Gene.
好极了
Excellent!
第二天重复前一天的内容
And the next day do it again--
唱相同的歌曲  吃不同的龙虾
same songs, different lobsters.
你们两个脑子被夹了是吧
What's the matter with you two?
那你说说  露易丝
Come on, Louise,
这是你想象中初次品尝龙虾的情景吗
is this really how you imagined your first time?
是啊
Yes.
好吧  不太符合
Okay, not quite.
州监狱
露易丝
Louise,
今天  你要为你犯下的滔天大罪
today, you pay the super price
付出昂贵的代价
for your super crimes.
好好享受你最后的晚餐吧
Enjoy your last meal.
看我的...
It'll do just fine...
飞天钳
in a pinch!
也许我们操之过急了
Maybe we have been rushing things.
我想等准备好了再吃
I want to wait till I'm ready.
别向这小妮子屈服
Let's not give in to peer pressure.
我们把龙虾放回到
Let's release the lobster
出售它的那家超市去吧
back into the supermarket from whence he came!
我想你们说的对
I guess you're right.
这家伙哪辈子修来的...  糟了
Looks like this guy's the one that got a... Whoa! Oops!
我们有龙虾吃了
I guess we're having lobster.
这是命中注定的
It was meant to be.
你结婚的时候
When you get married,
装成那是你第一次吃龙虾好了
just pretend it's your first time eating lobster.
没问题
No problem.
下来了
Down it comes!
这座精美绝伦的黄油雕像
This stunning butter sculpture,
是朱莉娅・柴尔德
the likeness of Julia Child,
它集众多黄油条块制作而成
was made from every available stick and pat of butter
远近的黄油都被用光了
within the local and outlying communities.
朱莉娅的脚下来了
And there goes Julia's feet!
什么  龙虾节又重新启动了
What?! Lobsterfest is back on?
我说伙计  你们不是要去参加龙虾节吧
Hey, guys, um, you're not going to Lobsterfest, are you?
我有困难了  伙计们
I'm in kind of a bind, fellas.
在我的餐馆里赫然躺着个邮筒
There's a mailbox in the middle of my restaurant.
你能帮我寄一下吗
Oh! Can you mail this for me?
等等  我说  伙计们
Wait. Hey, guys?
你来啦  哥们  雨果  你好啊
There he is, my buddy, Hugo! Hi.
-你好  鲍勃  -你好  鲍鲍
- Oh, hi, Bob. - Hi, Bobby.
你们两个要干嘛去
What are you both doing right now?
我的餐馆  昨晚不巧被毁掉了
My, uh, place, uh, happened to get destroyed last night.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Oh, really? - Yeah.
-我餐馆里...  -鲍勃  我非常忙
- In the middle of... - Bob, I'm very busy.
众桌浓汤等着我评判呢
I have tables and tables of bisque to judge.
昨晚是我给你们两个牵的线
Hey, I hooked you two up last night,
你们两个还弄坏了
and you guys kind of
浴室的婴儿换布台
broke the baby changing station in the bathroom.
来几句经典台词噎住他  雨果  我想看
Slap him with a citation, Hugo. I want to watch.
宝贝喜欢看我耀武扬威
Baby likes civil authority?
是啊
Yes, I love civil authority.
那我就耀下武扬下威
I'll show baby civil authority.
高跷男  你从我的窗户摔了进去
Stilts guy! You fell through my window.
遍地都是玻璃渣
Lot of glass on the floor.
-你要去哪  -我得走了  鲍勃
- Where you going? - Got to go, Bob!
如果我站的时间太久  会摔倒的
If I stay still too long, I fall over!
大家  等等  停下  等等  大家
People! Wait! Stop! Wait! People!
你们以为可以忽视我吗
Do you think you can just ignore me?!
就此次意外死亡而言
Well, as far as accidental death goes,
这只腿相当美味呀
this one was pretty tasty.
我觉得有点刺痛  你们有这种感觉吗
I feel tingly. Do you feel tingly?
我想他过敏了
I think he's having an allergic reaction.
我们得想想办法
We should do something.
好  我们坐到他身上看看他会不会弹起来
Yeah, let's sit on him and see if he pops.
不  我们得带他去龙虾节
No, we should take him to Lobsterfest.
那里有医疗所
They have a medical tent.
那样我就能吃到更多的龙虾
And I could get more lobster!
-把我弹起来啊  -我正在努力
- Oh, pop! - I'm trying!
下面由锦绣三重奏献上一曲
Let's hear it for John Van Horton and the music extrusion!
是我  鲍勃
Uh, it's me. Bob!
鲍勃  鲍勃  鲍勃
Bob. Bob. Bob.
好吧
Okay...
请安静
settle down.
发生什么了
Listen, what's going on here?
我们在干嘛
What are we doing?
我记得的最后一件事
Last thing I remember,
你们全都在我的餐馆里庆祝鲍堡节
you were all in my place and it was Bobsterfest.
我想回到那个时刻
I want to get back to that.
让我们回到那个时刻吧
Let's go back to that!
你们之中起码有四五十个人会跟我走
Or at the very least, 40 or 50 of you come with me right now
帮我清理餐馆吧
and help me clean up the restaurant!
不用一次全都来
Not all at once.
你自己清理吧
Clean it yourself!
老爸在龙虾节的舞台上呢
Whoa, dad's on the stage at Lobsterfest.
我看不见啊  给我详细描述一下
My eyes don't work. Paint me a word picture.
孩子们  你们在这里干嘛
Kids? What are you doing here?
没什么
Nothing.
吉恩是怎么了
What's wrong with Gene?
他看起来很吓人
He looks horrible.
他一直就这副德性
He looks like he always looks.
才不是呢  是这样吗
No, he doesn't. Does he?
好像是对什么过敏了...
Looks like an allergic...
你是不是吃龙虾了
Did you eat lobster?!
-我...  -他拒绝回答这个问题
- I, uh... -He refuses to answer that.
你们都是怎么了
What's wrong with you people!
-看看我儿子  -大家好
- Look at my son! - Hello.
这都怪你们
You did this!
和你们对龙虾变态的执着
You and your disgusting food fetish!
鲍勃  你给我下来
Bob, get off the stage!
你在破坏公共秩序
You're disorderly.
是么  那我是不是该破坏一下
Oh, yeah? Maybe I should get disorderly
这锅龙虾呢
with this lobster pot here.
没错  你们没听错
That's right, you heard me.
你们毁了我的店  我就要毁掉龙虾节
You trash my restaurant, I trash Lobsterfest,
就从这口煮虾锅开始
starting with this lobster pot.
我擦  好烫
Ow! It's hot.
算了  先放过它
Let's leave that alone.
哎哟  我看见了黄油
Oh, but I see some butter.
如果有谁弄脏这珍贵的黄油
You wouldn't like it
你们应该会不高兴吧
if someone messed with your precious butter!
把我这大毛脚趾伸进去如何啊
Like stuff a big, hairy toe in it!
鲍勃  慢慢地把脚放回到袜子里
Bob, put your foot back in your sock slowly.
我现在有权使用
I'm authorizing myself
这把全新的豆袋枪向你开枪
to use my brand-new beanbag gun to subdue you.
借过  不好意思  借过  借过
Excuse me, I'm sorry, excuse me, excuse me.
鲍勃  停下来  这不是你会做的事
Bob! No! This isn't you!
这就是我  琳达
This is me, Linda!
是他们把我逼成这样的
This is the "Me" that they made!
你看他们把我们的儿子弄成什么样了
And look what they did to our son.
他本来不长这样  是吗
That's not how he normally looks, is it?
鲍鲍  听我说
Bobby, listen to me.
借过  抱歉
Excuse me, I'm sorry, oh...
你不用过来了
You don't have to keep moving!
你并不卑微  鲍勃
You're not a bottom feeder, Bob!
对  我才不卑微呢
No, I'm not a bottom feeder.
我是汉堡男
I'm a burger man.
好吧  我要走了
All right, I'm leaving.
我知道你们都想让我离开
I'm sure that's what everybody wants.
如果我动一下会...  糟糕
Oh, what happens if I-- Oh, woops!
鲍鲍  你还好吗
Bobby, are you okay?
请让一下  借过
Excuse me, uh, excuse me.
我的上帝
Oh, my God!
整桶黄油都被鲍勃弄脏了
All the butter's been contaminated by Bob,
而且城里没有别的黄油了
and there isn't any more in town!
鲍勃搞砸了我们的龙虾节
Bob destroyed Lobsterfest!
你们就别沾黄油直接吃呗
Can't you just eat lobster without butter?
不行  怎么可能  太可恶了
No! How? That's an outrage!
既然如此  你们怎么不管它叫"黄油节"
Well, why don't you call it "butterfest"?
主角是虾不是黄油  混蛋
It brings out the succulence, jerk!
没错
Yeah!
我们得怎么处置他
So what should we do with him?
把他扔进虾壳堆里
Throw him in the shell pile!
虾壳堆
Shell pile?
虾壳堆  虾壳堆
Shell pile! Shell pile!
虾壳堆  虾壳堆  虾壳堆
Shell pile! Shell pile! Shell...
不是吧
Oh, boy.
请让一下  请让一下  抱歉
Excuse me, excuse me, sorry.
鲍勃是不该用污染黄油威胁你们
Maybe Bob shouldn't have threatened your butter,
而且他完全可以冲你们收汉堡钱
and he definitely should have charged you for the burgers.
昨晚他对你们慷慨相邀
But he opened his beautiful heart last night,
而你们却像煮龙虾一样把他的心意活煮了
and you boiled it alive like a lobster!
你这样说只会让我们更气愤
All you're doing is making us angrier!
龙虾壳堆
Shell pile!
抱歉  鲍鲍  我打错了比方
Sorry, Bobby, I used a bad analogy.
雨果  好像有点不对劲
Hugo, this doesn't seem right.
怎么了  我处上对象了
What? I have a girlfriend;
鲍勃也要被扔进虾壳堆里了
Bob's about to be thrown on to a shell pile--
跟我幻想过的场景一摸一样
I've had this exact fantasy.
别这样  雨果
Come on, Hugo.
昨晚要不是鲍勃帮你牵线搭桥
If Bob hadn't been your wingman last night,
你现在还是个身披肩带的孤独单身汉呢
you'd be another lonely guy in a satin sash.
我好得很
I was doing fine!
我才不需要谁给我牵线
I don't need a wingman!
是么
Oh, no?
红郎
Wingman,
振翅伴您左右
flying with the eagles.
红郎
Wingman,
助您一臂之力
he's trying to help you out.
红郎
Wingman,
红郎  红郎
wingman, wingman,
wingman, wingman...
够了  罗恩
Agh! Damn it, Ron!
好了  大家听我说
All right, attention, people!
停下来  都给我停下来
Stop it, everyone! Slow down!
我是卫生检查员
I'm the health inspector.
有人曾说我好比食品治安官
Someone once told me that's like being the food sheriff.
鲍勃有没有毁掉这桶黄油
This vat of butter isn't contaminated by Bob
要待我调查之后才能定夺
until I say so!
我这儿有个奶制品纯度检测仪
I have with me a dairy purity spectrometer.
现在  让我来检测一下
Now, give me some room.
让他好好检测一下
Give him some room!
谢谢你  格雷琴
Thank you, Gretchen.
你干嘛扎我
Ow! You stabbed me!
给你扎了针肾上腺素
That's just epinephrine.
你刚才只是过敏性休克了
You're in anaphylactic shock.
你这只虾长得挺带感嘛
Mm, you're a handsome shrimp.
我这有张世界末日交配名单
You just jumped to the top of my list.
我刚刚把你排在了前面
It's a mating list for when the world ends.
-你的电邮能给我吗  -不行
- Can I get your e-mail? - No.
检测结果已经出来了
I have finished my butter analysis.
鲍勃的皮屑  臂毛  以及指甲泥
Bob's skin flakes, arm hair and fingernail dirt
都检测到了
are all present.
不是吧
No!
我还没说完
Let me finish!
虽然都检测到了  但还不至于构成威胁
They're present, but not at threatening levels.
黄油等级为C到D-之间
The butter is grade C to D-.
除婴儿和免疫力低下人群以外
Fit for everyone except babies
大家可以放心食用
and people with compromised immune systems.
我是说  系上你的围嘴吧
In other words, get your bib on!
这真是有史以来最棒的一次龙虾节
Man, that was the best Lobsterfest ever.
看来大家都是
Yeah. Turns out people are hard on the outside
刀子嘴豆腐心啊
and soft on the inside.
就像是...
Like, uh...
像是...
like, uh...
我不知道啦  就像是...  螃蟹
Oh, I don't know, like a... like a crab.
没错  大家就像螃蟹
Yup. People are just like crabs.
我们还目睹了一项新传统的诞生
And we witnessed the birth of a new tradition--
那就是在每年龙虾节前夜搞砸鲍勃的店
every year on Lobsterfest Eve, we trash Bob's place.
-不不不不  -是吧
- No, no, no, no. - Right?
现在就开砸吧
Let's start now!
吉恩  你发誓你没吃过龙虾
Gene, you swear you didn't have lobster?
你一直长成这样
You've always looked like this?
我生来就是这副模样
I was born like this.
我得拿照片对比一下
Uh, I need a picture to compare.
我的上帝
Oh, my God,
你确实生来就是这副模样
you do always look like this.
你好  帅哥
Hello, gorgeous!
-鲍勃  琳达  -你好  雨果
- Bob, Linda. - Hey, Hugo.
格雷琴呢
Where's Gretchen?
那个叫格雷琴的真是活力十足啊
She's a firecracker, that Gretchen.
你能驾驭她吗  雨果
You sure she's not more than you can handle, Hugo?
她刚刚把我甩了
Gretchen just broke up with me.
她说我驾驭不了她
She said she was more than I could handle.
场面很尴尬
Oh. It was ugly.
她说她并不介意勋章的大小
She said she didn't mind a small badge,
但关键问题是我不懂怎么利用  鲍勃
but said I didn't know how to use it, Bob!
那真是太糟了
Oh, that's too bad.
我不需要你的同情
I don't need your pity!
我来这是想
So, here we are.
搞个突击检查
Surprise inspection!
-铅笔  -铅笔
- Pencil! - Pencil.
-本子  -本子
- Pad! - Pad.
哎哟  票插弯了  罗恩  封店
Ooh, bent spindle. Ron! Shut it down!